[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
We'll close off this module by exploring a little bit more detail.
سنختم هذه الوحدة من خلال استكشاف المزيد من التفاصيل.
I'll try example of decision trees and
سأجرب مثالاً على أشجار القرارات
comparing it to our example of logistic regression from before.
وأقارنه مع مثال على الانحدار اللوجستي السابق.
Here is the example that we will consider,
ها هو المثال الذي سندرسه،
is one that we considered in the logistic regression module.
هو الذي درسناه في وحدة الانحدار اللوجستي.
We're taking this dataset here and fitting
سنأخذ مجموعة البيانات الواردة هنا هذه وسنقوم بمطابقة
a logistic regression, decision boundary is on the right here.
انحدار لوجستي، يكون حد القرار على الجانب الأيمن هنا.
And we can see the parameters that we learned from data.
ويمكنك رؤية المتغيرات التي توصلنا إليها من البيانات.
So this is if we just did a simple degree one polynomial
وهذا إذا قمنا فحسب بإجراء خاصية كثير الحدود بسيطة
feature is just going to straight up linear features.
من الدرجة الأولى، فسينطلق مباشرة إلى الخواص الخطية.
Let's see what happens when we build a decision stump on the same data.
لنرى ما يحدث عندما نقوم بإنشاء فرع قرار على نفس البيانات.
So If you do a single level decision tree and you apply to this data set,
لذلك، إذا أجريت شجرة قرار ذات مستوى واحد وقمت بتطبيقها على مجموعة البيانات هذه،
what we'll do is we'll split on x1 and if you try out the threshold
فما سنقوم به هو أننا سنقسم x1 وإذا جربت قيم
values you'll see that on the left side we'll have x1 less than- 0.07 and
الحد، فسترى أنه على الجانب الأيسر سيكون لدينا x1 أصغر من - 0.07
on the right side will be x1 greater than- 0.07.
وعلى الجانب الآخر ستكون x1 أكبر من - 0.07.
You see for the ones on the right.
ترى أنه للقيم الموجودة على الجانب الأيمن.
We have more positive examples so
لدينا مزيد من الأمثلة الموجبة، لذلك
we're going to predict positive, while the ones on the left,
سنقوم بتوقع إيجابية بينما لتلك القيم الموجود على الجانب الأيسر،
we have more negative examples, so we're going to predict negative.
لدينا أمثلة سالبة أكثر، لذلك سنتوقع سلبية.
And you'll see that they correspond.
وسترى أنها تكون متوافقة.
So here's our split.
حسنًا ها هو الانقسام خاصتنا.
- 0.07.
- 0.07.
This first left on the tree will correspond to points on the left there,
وسيتوافق هذا الجانب الأيسر الأول على الشجرة مع النقاط على اليسار هناك.
and the second one will correspond to points on the right.
وسيتوافق الجانب الثاني مع النقاط على اليمين.
Extremely twittered.
أمر بديهي للغاية.
So unlike, rational we're able to get the diagonal decision boundary.
لذا على خلاف، الأمر النسبي يمكننا الحصول على حد القرار المائل.
Here we're only going to get straight up, or straight across, decision boundary.
سنحصل هنا على حد قرار مستقيم لأعلى أو مستقيم بالعرض فقط.
At least in the first split.
في الانقسام الأول على الأقل.
Now, if we keep going with the degree of the algorithm, and we take another split
والآن إذا واصلنا بدرجة اللوغاريتم، وأجرينا انقسامًا آخر
for each one of these intermediate nodes, we'll see that for
لكل من هذه العقد الوسيطة، فسنلاحظ أنه
the data where x1 is less than- 0.07, we might split on x1 again,
للبيانات حيث x1 تكون أصغر من - 0.07، قد نجري انقسامًا على x1 مجددًا،
and make predictions which in this case would be splitting on x1,
ونجري توقعًا والذي في هذه الحالة سيكون منقسمًا على x1،
less than- 1.66, and on both cases,
أصغر من - 1.66ـ، وفي كلتا الحالتين،
we're predicting to be- 1,
سنتوقع أن يكون - 1،
so a negative data point, so- 1,- 1.
لذلك نقطة بيانات سالبة، وبالتالي - 1,- 1.
But for x1 greater than- 0.07,
ولكن بالنسبة إلى x1 أكبر من- 0.07،
we now split on x2, whether it's bigger than or
تجري الآن انقسامًا على x2، سواء كانت أكثر من أو
greater than 1.55, which in our split on our data is over here, 1.55.
أكبر من 1.55، وهو ما يرد هنا في الانقسام الخاص بنا على بياناتنا، 1.55.
That's where x2 would be.
وذلك حيث ستكون x2.
And we see that now we have, for the data which is smaller than 1.55, in x2,
ونرى أنه لدينا الآن، للبيانات الأصغر من 1.55، في x2،
we have 11 positive examples, so we predict + 1.
يكون لدينا 11 مثالًا موجبًا، لذلك نتوقع + 1.
But for the data which is greater than 1.55,
ولكن للبيانات التي تكون أكبر من 1.55،
we have three negative examples, so we predict- 1.
يكون لدينا أمثلة سالبة، لذلك نتوقع- 1.
And so now we have a much more interesting region so
وبالتالي لدينا الآن مجال أكثر إثارة للاهتمام، لذلك
the split, these two nodes here on the right, one corresponds to this
الانقسام بحيث تتوافق إحدى العقدتين هنا على الجانب الأيمن مع
big green area and the other one corresponds to this little box on the top.
المنطقة الخضراء الكبيرة هذه وتتوافق الأخرى مع هذا المربع الصغير في الأعلى.
And we can imagine continuing this process, splitting again and
ويمكننا تصور مواصلة هذه العملية إجراء الانقسام مرة
again and again as we'll see next, but one important thing to know
تلو أخرى حسبما سترى لاحقًا، ولكن الأمر المهم هو معرفة
is that when you have continuous variables and And this is a really important point.
أنه عندما يكون لدينا متغيرات متصلة وهذه نقطة مهمة للغاية.
Unlike for discrete ones or
على خلاف تلك المنفصلة أو
for categorical ones, we can split on the same variable multiple times.
تلك الفئوية، يمكننا إجراء الانقسام على نفس المتغير لعدة مرات.
So we can split the next one and split the next one again, or we can split the next
وبالتالي يمكننا إجراء الانقسام على المتغير التالي والمتغير التالي مجددُا، أو يمكننا إجراء الانقسام
one and the next two, then the next one and again, and we'll see that.
على المتغير التالي والمتغيرين التاليين ثم المتغير التالي مجددُا، وسنرى ذلك.
So in this example that we talked about,
لذا في هذا المثال الذي تحدثنا بشأنه،
we can keep the decision tree learning process growing.
يمكننا مواصلة تنمية عملية التعلم الخاصة بشجرة القرارات.
So in Depth 1 we just get a decision stump which corresponds to the vertical
لذا في العمق 1، نحصل فقط على فرع قرار يتوافق مع الخط
line that we drew in the beginning- 0.07.
العمودي الذي رسمناه في البداية - 0.07.
If we go to Depth 2, we get this little box that contains most of the positive
وإذا ذهبنا إلى العمق 2، نحصل على هذا المربع الصغير، الذي يحتوي على معظم الأمثلة
examples but it is still some misclassifications over here, and then
الموجبة، ولكن ما يزال هناك بعض التصنيفات الخاطئة هنا،
if you kept going, splitting, splitting, splitting, splitting, splitting,
ثم إذا واصلت إجراء انقسام، انقسام، انقسام، انقسام، انقسام.
splitting all the way to Depth 10, we get this really crazy decision boundary.
انقسام وصولًا إلى العمق 10 فسنحصل على حد القرار الجنوني للغاية هذا.
And if you look at it carefully, what you'll see is that, and I'm going to
وإذا نظرت إلى الأمر بعناية، فما ستراه هو أنني سأقوم
draw over the decision boundary here, but if you look at it a little bit carefully,
بالرسم فوق حد القرار هنا، ولكن إذا نظرت إليه بشكل أكثر عناية قليلًا،
you'll see that it basically makes, no mistakes, so it has 0 training error.
فسترى أنه لا يقوم بأي أخطاء في الأساس، لذلك يكون به 0 خطأ تدريب.
And we can compare what we saw with Logistic Regression with
ويمكننا مقارنة ما رأيناه من خلال الانحدار اللوجستي
what we're seeing with Decision Trees, and understand again, in preview for
مع ما نراه من خلال شجر القرارات والفهم مرة أخرى، كعرض مسبق على
what we will see next module, kind of the notion of overfitting.
ما سنراه في الوحدة التالية، نوعًا من مفهوم إفراط المطابقة.
So, in Logistic Regression we started with Degree 1 parameter features, and
حسنًا، بدأنا في الانحدار اللوجستي بخواص متغير من الدرجة 1
we saw in Degree 2 had a really nice fit of the data, is a nice parable.
ورأينا أنه في الدرجة 2 كانت هناك مطابقة بيانات جيدة للغاية، فهو مثل جيد.
You didn't get everything right, but you did pretty well.
لم تحصل على كل شيء بشكل صحيح، ولكن أحسنت صنعًا.
And the degree six polynomial had a really crazy decision boundary.
وكان بالخاصة متعددة الحدود من الدرجة ستة حد قرار جنوني للغاية.
It got zero training error, but I didn't really trust those predictions,
فكان لديه 0 خطأ تدريب، ولكني لا أثق تمامًا في هذه التوقعات،
we didn't really trust those prediction.
لم نثق تمامًا في هذه التوقعات.
With the decision tree, what you control is the depth of the decision tree and
من خلال شجرة القرار، يكون ما تتحكم فيه هو عمق شجرة القرار
so Depth 1 was just a decision stamp.
وهكذا كان العمق 1 هو فرع قرار.
It didn't do so well.
لم يكن أداؤه جيدًا.
If you go to Depth 3, it looks like a little bit of a jagged line, but
إذا ذهب إلى العمق 3، يبدو مثل خط متعرج قليلًا ولكنه
it looks like a pretty nice decision boundary.
يبدو مثل حد قرار جيد للغاية.
It makes a few mistakes, but it looks pretty good.
وهو يقوم ببعض الأخطاء ولكنه يبدو جيدًا جدًا.
If you look at Depth 10, you get this crazy decision boundary,
وإذا نظرت إلى العمق 10، تحصل على حد القرار الجنوني هذا،
has zero training error, but is likely to be over fitting.
الذي به 0 خطأ تدريب، ولكن من المرجح أن يكون مفرطًا في المطابقة.
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]